As app developers, it's our job to maintain the illusion that once started,
every app is waiting patiently in the background looking for
its chance to be the star when called on. So whenever the user switches back to
your app, whether or not the system is kilted in the interim,
they should be presented with the same UI they had when they left. To help,
Android has a pair of handles specifically for persisting state in these
circumstances. On save instance data is called immediately before on pause. So
as soon as your app is no longer active, an on
restore instance data is called immediately after on create, but
only if the app is being restarted after having been terminated by the system.
That means you can read the bundle of state information saved the last time your
app was moved to the foreground here. The next time,
you'll use the switches to your app even if it was killed by the system in
the mean time. Using that bundle you can return your ui to the same state it
was the last time the user saw it creating a seamless transition that hides
the resource management happening under the covers. That's enough of the why,
let's go back to Dan and see how to put this theory into practice.